[Music]
Hello everyone. I hope you're having a
wonderful holiday season. We had
plummeting temperatures this week, overg
-30 at one point, and consequently, I
was pretty cooped up indoors and unable
to enjoy nature in the same way I
usually do.
I compromised on this week's video in
order to bring you a simple little Q&A.
I hope you enjoy it and hopefully soon I
will be out in nature once again and be
able to share its treasures with you.
[Music]
Hello. I hope the holiday season is
treating you well. I was planning on
uploading this video a while ago, but I
got caught up in holiday celebrations.
It got extremely cold and we were having
flickering power and power outages. And
I decided to sit down and make something
a little cozier and simpler just for
this week. And if more chatty videos are
not your cup of tea, no worries at all.
I will see you next week with my more
usual content. I have been working on
some videos that really mean a lot to
me. So, I'm very excited to share them
with you. I have been meaning to do a
Q&A video for such a long time. There
are a lot of new fairy friends and
magical creatures in this little corner
of the world. And so I wanted to say
hello and introduce myself but also
answer some questions that have been
following this channel around for a
couple years now. I will recap a couple
basic things though. One is that my name
is Paola and I live in a rural valley in
Washington state in the US. I live here
with my husband Luke. He is a land
surveyor in this local area as well as
my pets Iger and Mavi. I did lose a dear
sweet bunny this year. His name was Mr.
Darcy and he was very close to my heart
and it's been difficult not having him.
So, I do hope to have maybe a bunny
again in the future, hopefully next
year. So, one of the first questions I
had is what do you do for work? And the
answer to that is that I do a variety of
things. I have been working on the
weekends at my little local bookstore,
but that is definitely the smallest part
of what I do. I run an Etsy shop. That
is definitely my main job and something
I'm incredibly grateful for to be able
to do. I make mostly kind of children's
inspired art and fairy art as well as
just nature art in general. And of
course, I make videos here on YouTube
and that is definitely a very important
part of the work I do. I don't do
sponsored content, so definitely my Etsy
shop is kind of my main job and my main
way that I'm able to make a living. I
like to do a variety of jobs. Many
people in this little valley actually do
that. They diversify just to make things
work. And so, it's been always
interesting to evolve. I am uncertain
that I will be able to continue working
at my little bookshop because I have
time commitments in other places in my
life currently. So, I may not be working
there for the new year, but I hope to
work there again in the future because I
really, really enjoy it. Another
question was, "What is your favorite
meal?" And I will answer that. I don't
necessarily have a favorite meal, but I
have many, many favorite desserts. I
love cream brulee. I love ice cream. I
love sweet drinks. I am just a sweet
tooth. Such a sweet tooth. Favorite
meals? I would say probably stir fries
and sushi. I'm not able to get a lot of
those foods here locally because we're
very limited in our restaurants. I also
love a good pasta dish. Another question
was, "What are your favorite children's
books?" I have so many, so I can't
possibly choose. However, some very
favorites that come to mind are Journey,
Maybe, and the Bramblely Hedge books are
really adorable as well, as well as, of
course, the Peter Rabbit books. Another
question was, "What are your goals for
the new year?" I haven't quite decided
what I want to do for the new year quite
yet. However, I do really want to
consistently keep a journal. I have
always wanted to be able to do that, and
I've never been very successful. And so,
I'm going to attempt to do that next
year. And I think my goal every year
pretty much is to continue discovering
how to create a very healthy work life
balance. I am someone who tends to
overdo it on work, and so I'm always
trying to reel myself back a little bit.
How did you find your property was
another question. I was very very very
lucky because the properties in this
area as well as so many places in the
states are so extremely expensive right
now and it is very difficult to be able
to afford it. My husband and I looked
out as he was born and raised in this
little valley and his parents moved here
uh way before it got this expensive and
so they had a property right next to
them that had a barn on it that they
renovated. They were able to sell it to
us at a price that we could afford and
to this day we're just so incredibly
grateful that we had that opportunity
and that we had family nearby. Another
question was, I see that you worked in
customer service. How have the holidays
been? That is a very considerate
question. A lot of customer service
workers are working overtime and working
so hard during the holiday season. It
can be absolutely exhausting. So, if you
have the opportunity to give some
festive well-wishes to a customer
service worker, I know that they will
appreciate it. While it did get quite
busy at my little bookstore, it was at
no point overwhelming, which was really
nice cuz I've worked at customer service
jobs where there have been people lined
up for, you know, yards. And so, that
was very stressful. So, thankfully, this
was a really lovely Christmas for me,
despite it, of course, being a busy one.
You know, I was working Christmas Eve,
so I did enjoy it. It's really lovely to
spend time with my co-workers, but it is
not always easy. Do you have any advice
for people who also want to be teachers
or child care workers? I used to be a
childare worker. It is what I moved over
to this valley to do. I was a teacher at
a little independent school. I really
loved it. It was just wonderful. But I
will say, you know, when you are working
with well over a dozen children,
sometimes up to 16 or more, not only
physically are you moving up and down
and doing things all day long, it can be
difficult to take breaks because there
are children in your care and of course
they come first and their safety comes
first. Children also very much respond
to how you are doing emotionally. And so
it's really important to regulate your
emotions and you know really help create
a good atmosphere in the classroom even
if you're having a difficult day or
something's happening in your personal
life. So it is um definitely I have so
much respect for childare workers and
teachers. It's just such a amazing job.
The people that do it are incredible and
they definitely should be appreciated
more. It is such incredible work and
such vital work for our future. How did
you learn about foraging and wild foods?
The answer to that is kind of simple. I
I I just kind of learned as I went. I
definitely can look back at some very
old videos and see things that kind of I
did incorrectly. I definitely was
learning about wildcrafting and foraging
as I was making these videos. And of
course, I knew I was going to make
mistakes. However, a combination of
things really helped me. There were a
couple books that were written by a
local author here that really helped me
get a start and just jumping in and, you
know, asking questions and being
curious, finding people that also are
passionate about it. And it takes a lot
of learning and it takes a long time
before you can gain confidence in plant
identification and how to use them. But
you do get there eventually if you have
the perseverance. Another question was
that are you going to quit YouTube soon?
Um the answer is no. I do hope to
continue making videos for quite a while
longer. However, I think that as with
many of these sorts of careers, there's
going to be an end point. So, I'm just
doing my best to enjoy every week and
communicate with all of you and really
appreciate all the kind words and
feedback, you know, while we have this
right now. I do not know. I can't tell.
I don't know what the future's going to
hold. This was an interesting question
that I got and it was, "I love reading,
but I have a hard time concentrating due
to being distracted by technology. Do
you have any advice?" I like that
question because I think it is something
that a lot of us deal with. I know that
there have been times in my life when
I've had a hard time concentrating on
reading, especially in school when I was
just so busy. I think something that
helped me was really just to create a
very designated time even if it was just
10 minutes to half an hour, maybe an
hour. I would really recommend that you
know really try a variety of different
books and see what you enjoy. There is
comedy, there is drama, there's mystery,
there's more simpler style books, more
complicated, and really remember that I
think it's important not to feel
obligation to continue reading a book if
it's just not speaking to you. I also
love kind of creating a ritual where I
light a candle. I might put on some
music unless it bothers you. And I love
putting on some ambient music. There's
some really awesome things on YouTube.
You can look up ambient rooms or ambient
playlist for any type of atmosphere that
matches the book you're reading. Reading
is not a necessarily superior hobby to
any other hobby. You know, if I want to
spend my evening painting instead of
reading, that is just as valid. I think
sometimes we see reading as a very kind
of um fruitful activity and a very
important thing for us to do, but you
know there's a lot of equally important
sorts of hobbies that we could spend our
time doing as well. So never connect not
reading as failing in some shape or
form. This question also connects a bit
to another one which is how do you
de-stress? And it is kind of usually a
similar thing. I have more than ever
recently put it upon myself to really
prioritize taking a little bit of time
to write a little bit in a journal, to
listen to some calming music and
meditate or spend time kind of in uh a
more spiritual space. That time spent in
relaxation is very important for the
success of the rest of your day. We can
be productive and arguably we might be
able to be even more productive or at
least more happy to be productive if we
do prioritize a little bit of that time
for the sake of our psychological and
physical health as well. Do you have any
favorite music? I have a kind of variety
of music I like to listen to. However, I
most often gravitate towards more
ambient music and music that helps me
concentrate on whatever I'm doing. I do
a lot of work. I spend a lot of time
painting as well as working on my
computer. I really love some of the
albums of Priscilla an as well as Katie
Malua. They have very soft, very
beautiful voices that always calm me
down. I also like, of course,
soundtracks to amazing movies. I love
course a lot of Studio Geekly, a lot of
Lord of the Rings, all types of things.
I love this question. What is your
favorite tea? I really love just any
type of tea that is floral. Jasmine tea.
I think I had some sort of lotus flower
tea recently that was delicious. I just
I love floral teas. Another question is
do you work out? I um I do not I have I
am however active. I don't know what
would constitute necessarily working out
or not working out but um I do love to
go on nature walks. I go on them almost
every day. In the winter, I'm a little
more yeah, just a lovely little hike or
a walk. Um, I'm not really a workout
sort of person in general. So, that's
just kind of the way that I stay active
and mobile and just I love doing work
that keeps me moving. So, I guess I just
move throughout the day.
How are you not scared of wild animals
living out in the forest? I see this
question fairly often. I assume it comes
from people who have not lived out in
rural areas. Um, through my experience
and through the experience of most
people who I talk to, um, you know, wild
animals really just want to be left
alone and they want to be respected and
it is, uh, very rare, extremely rare for
an animal to be intentionally aggressive
towards you in any way. For example, we
have bears are a pretty common sighting
around here. And pretty much all they
want to do is just eat the berries out
of your tree and take a nap on the lawn.
You know, you definitely want to avoid
them and give them their space, but
they're not trying to be aggressive. The
amount of incidences are so incredibly
low. For example, compare the amount of
people that are attacked by a wild
animal to the amount of people who are
attacked by other humans. It is a very
telling comparison.
Do you prefer the forest or your
previous cottage on the prairie? I would
say I love both for different reasons.
The prairie was really wonderful. If you
walked through for enough time, you
could see little quail nests and all
sorts of little signs of life and I
really love that. However, here in the
forest, it is so beautiful and it's much
cooler in the summer as well. I love
both. But of course, right now, I'm
really appreciating being surrounded by
trees. It just feels like a big hug.
What are five things we didn't know
about you? I like this question. It's so
random. I once won a local version of
the reading rainbow competition. I think
it was only um aired in my state. I
don't know. I assume it was aired in my
state or maybe only in my local area,
but I won one of the reading rainbow
competitions when I was really little
and I got to read my book on KCTS. So,
somewhere in some archives, there's a
video of me reading my book that I wrote
and illustrated, and it um I think was
called Tail Tales, and it was about this
island called the island of Bingo
where cats and dogs live together, and
it was kind of a legend. So, it was a
very strange story. If I ever find that
book, I'm sure I have it somewhere here.
I will read it to you. I used to also
compete a little bit in rabbit shows
when I was a kid. There was a kid
version of rabbit showing where you
would just bring your pet rabbit and you
would train your little rabbit to sit
very properly and you would answer
questions about your rabbit to a judge.
And I used to do that. It was with a 4
program which is pretty popular here in
the states and it was uh really fun. But
it led me to knowing a very strangely
large amount of information about
rabbits. My best friend growing up was
over 60 years old and she was my art
teacher and we would spend sometimes the
weekends together quilting and um yeah
just baking and painting and having fun
and um I have so many lovely memories of
her. I can speak English, Spanish and
heringa. If you know what heringa is,
you probably are Hispanic.
Um the fifth thing, um I absolutely love
sparkling water. If it could come out of
the faucet, I would be so happy.
How did you know you wanted to marry
your husband? I definitely knew my
husband was someone that I wanted in my
life when I realized how safe I felt
around him and how I felt so seen and so
respected. I just really appreciated
that and I wanted to get that in return
because I appreciated it so much. And
I've known what it's like to be in
relationships where I felt unsafe and
not respected whatsoever.
And I've just always loved that about
him. He's also a very caring and very
authentic person and very kind of
generous with his emotions and his time.
Another question was, "What is your
favorite dress and do you have any
advice for creating a wardrobe you
love?" I don't have a favorite dress.
I'll put in a clips of a couple of my
favorites just because they're very
wellm made and they fit me um in a way
that is comfortable. I love going to
thrift shops. I also love um doing kind
of assorted thrift shopping online.
Thread Up is a website that I have used
in the past to find some discounted
pieces. However, I would say that it is
so important to be comfortable in your
clothing because if you are adjusting
your clothing or just very fixated on
something that's uncomfortable, it
really kind of um you know puts your
energy more inward and more
self-conscious. And I think it's so
important to just feel comfortable in
your own skin and clothes that help you
feel that way, you know, and it'll be so
much easier to be confident. I had one
last question and that was how do I deal
with uh cyber bullying or you know
negative people in general in my real
life or online and that is a tricky one
to answer because I think it depends on
you know the person and your personality
and what you're able to handle and what
you're able to let go of. It has not
always been easy for me to deal with
bullies in person or online, but it does
really help me to remember that that
saying, what is it? Hurt people hurt
people, I think is how that saying goes,
that it helps to remember that people's
negative actions towards you often say a
lot more about them than they do about
you. And I think it's very important
especially when it comes to bullying
online to be able to unplug when
necessary to be able to step away from
that sphere and you know really ground
yourself. Working online you get your
fair share of bullying and I I I do find
that it has really deeply helped me to
just remember that you know happy people
don't want to go and say hateful words
towards other people. you know, those
people are really struggling and they're
going through something and it really
isn't about you at the end of the day.
And while it's easier said than done,
that does mean that you should do your
best to try to not let those words, you
know, define you. They can hurt and
that's totally normal to have that
feeling of hurt. I have come to accept
that it is totally okay to feel pain in
your heart when people are very unkind
to you. But I've also, you know, really
tried to use it to inspire me to just,
you know, do something extra that day to
be kind to someone else in a way almost
like balancing out those very unkind
words with kind words. And remembering
that no matter what you do, there will
be people who will not like what you're
doing. No matter who you are, there will
be people who don't like who you are for
one reason or another. Sometimes there
will be people who don't even give you
the opportunity to offer who you are or
what you do and they will just make a
judgment right off the bat. Perhaps it's
easier to put yourself out there and try
new things and get out of your comfort
zone if you know ahead of time that that
sort of thing will always happen and no
matter what you do, you know, there
will, you know, be people who don't
understand. So, you really need to try
to put your best foot forward and focus
on the positive. To not suppress those
feelings of pain, to acknowledge them
and understand that that's normal to
feel hurt when people say unkind things,
but to continue having courage, you
know, and trying to move forward despite
it. Yes, take it from someone who has
been making videos for quite a while.
You're never going to be able to please
everyone. There will always be people as
well that misunderstand your intentions
or your words and you just can't prevent
it. And that is, I think, a lifetime
journey of being able to continue
letting things go.
But there's no shame in feeling that
hurt and, you know, feeling that way.
That is totally okay. I've always, you
know, I've always had trouble with that
statement of just grow a thick skin
because I think for some people, you
know, we're always going to be in touch
with our emotions and we're always going
to have moments where we feel hurt. And
I think it's more about how we respond
to those feelings and whether or not we
let them define our view of other people
or define the view of ourselves that,
you know, is so much more important.
there's so much positivity, but as well
like useful feedback and constructive
criticism that you can take to heart a
lot more. And I think those people um
deserve a lot more of your time and
energy, of course, right? And you
energy. And the more time and focus you
put on these negative words, the more
that's taking away from you and your
ability to enjoy your present. So,
I think that's all I can say, but it's a
complicated one. I still struggle with
it. I still don't feel like I have the
answers there, but I am with you and I
do feel for you and I understand.
So, yes, I think those were all the
questions that I had written down. I
hope that this felt like a cozy little
tea party, and I hope to see you very
soon in one of my more usual types of
videos. I've been very excited to
showcase the winter wonderland over
here. It has been incredible.
As you can see, I have some St. John's
wart and eucalyptus that I've been
trying out to try to make into some
craft projects. So, there are a lot of
fun little ideas on the horizon. Thank
you so much for joining me. I hope you
have a wonderful new year. Do let me
know if you have any resolutions or
goals. Sending you all the well wishes.
Take care of yourselves and I will see
you very soon.
Goodbye.
[Music]